## Steven Gutierrez

Modesto, CA | 209-620-4804 | stevengbmv@gmail.com LinkedIn | Github | Blog

#### **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

Full Stack Developer with experience in Ruby, JavaScript and React based programming and a background in the retail industry. Acquired valuable insights and hands-on experience in the field, by applying my skills developing web pages for business clients. Solid foundation in software engineering principles, software design, communication, product testing, and adaptability in new environments. Excited to apply coding skills and problem-solving acumen in a professional setting.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

React · Object-Relational Mapping (ORM) · MVC · Ruby · SQL · Redux · Ruby on Rails · CSS · JavaScript · HTML · Tailwind CSS · Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) · JSON · RESTful API · Active Record

### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

# Recipe Share - Github | Demo | Website

Full Stack application providing users a platform to post their favorite recipes and a customizable user profile

- Designed front-end with React/Redux allowing separation of concerns and scalability
- Developed Rails API back-end to handle functional logic, data persistence/schema, authorize and authenticate users
- Implemented Active Record Validations ensuring accurate and valid data from user inputs
- Integrated image upload system for user profiles, Amazon Web Services data storage bucket for production

# Movie Review - Github | Demo

User reviews on favorite movies and customization of personal profiles

- Created a back-end API with Ruby on Rails
- Built front-end with React ensuring a clean and organized front-end UI
- Utilized Active Record Validations to ensure valid data was saved to the database
- Followed RESTful conventions ensuring client-server separation of concerns

### Hat Reviewer - Github | Demo

Admin-focused hat shop application allowing customization for products and reviews.

- Integrated Sinatra API to handle backend logic
- Added full CRUD implementation for Review Model
- Incorporated React for an efficient front-end
- Utilized Sqlite3 database to store data effectively

### **EXPERIENCE**

# Costco Wholesale, Modesto, CA

Merchant

06/2020 - Present

- Provide display recommendations that have resulted in an increase of 19% of sales in the Fresh Foods Department.
- Maintain warehouse layout to maximize efficiency and easy access to products through standardized display practices.
- Utilize on-site inventory management system to predict future customer buying trends and plan merchandise displays.
- Perform bi-annual inventory audits minimizing shrinkage and ensuring accurate inventory data.
- Train new employees in merchandising, customer service, safety and company best practices.

### Rent A Bin, Modesto, CA

11/2023 - Present

Freelance Web Developer

- Developed front-end with React and Tailwind CSS
- Built back-end services using Firebase including: Realtime DB, Functions, Firestore DB, User Authentication
- Maintain and modify existing site to ensure quick load time and implement new features effectively

### **EDUCATION**

## Flatiron School, Online

01/2024

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

# University of California, Davis, Davis, CA

08/2019 - 05/2020

Coursework completed towards a Bachelor of Arts in Economics

## Modesto Junior College, Modesto, CA

08/2016 - 05/2019

Completed general education coursework to transfer into an Economics degree program